Kevin Crawford

1553 Magnolia Drive Crystal Lake, Illinois 600014 312.593.6825 kevin@kevin-crawford.com Website: kevin-crawford.com

Think Design.

My core strengths are product innovation, design thinking, and delivering quality user experiences.

I have a unique blend of skills spanning from design and ideation through technical execution. My background is rooted in Industrial Design and my career has touched Corporate Identity, Marketing, Graphic/Interaction Design and User Experience.

My goal is to help grow a team of designers and engineers who share my enthusiasm for creating industry-changing products and services.

Key Attributes

- Product ideation balancing user needs, business goals, and technical feasibility
- Managing and mentoring UX designers and UI developers
- Team building and identifying needs and ideal candidates
- Bridging communication between end users, designers and engineers
- Interaction design with extensive B2B and mobile experience

Methodologies

- User Centered Design
- Design Thinking
- Lean Startup/Lean UX
- Test-Driven Development
- Agile Development

Experience

Manager, User Experience & Design

WHEELS INC. (2005 - PRESENT)

Wheels Inc. provides comprehensive fleet management services to organizations around the world.

- Responsible for the strategic redesign of Wheels' Client and Driver web applications
- Identified key areas for innovation to drive growth and business value
- Drove the adoption of a more customer centric approach to design and business strategy
- Transformed the UX and Design team to work more effectively with Marketing, Product Management,
 Sales and Engineering
- Managed a multi-disciplinary team of 10 people (UX, Visual Design, UI Developers and PM)
- Conducted a comprehensive client experience research project
- Produced designs for several industry award winning products

Creative/Technical Consultant

NERVANA GROUP, INC. (2012 – PRESENT)

Nervana Group provides unique experiences and innovative technology to the world's hands, to customers' lobbies, dining rooms, and campuses.

- Responsible for the design of several Nervana Groups flagship products including the GhostWall,
 MixBoard and Social iPad Menus
- Lead a multi-disciplinary team of 6 people (UX, Visual Design, UI Developers)
- Conducted comprehensive user experience research for touch enabled displays

Creative Director

TOUCH TASTE TECHNOLOGIES, INC. (2009 – 2012)

Touch Taste Technologies, Inc. is a startup incubator concentrating on innovative products for the entertainment and service industries.

- Lead design for our TouchLife table interface which won a Chicago Innovation Award
- Responsible for visual design, interface design, and usability research
- Owned the end-to-end user experience for all interactive services and products
- Lead a team of designers, engineers and marketing professionals

Co-Founder, CTO

MDOG (2005 – 2008)

mDog provides mobile technology adopted by many leading content providers including: NASDAQ, Wall Street Journal, Forbes, IDG Publishing Network, Nielsen Business Media, Ziff Davis Media, Crain's Communication, and Careerbuilder.

- Key contributor to the company's strategy and planning
- Consulted with clients on consumer awareness, marketing, and partnership strategies related to their mobile initiatives
- Responsible for technology implementation and defining our software development methodology
- Operational management responsibilities included recruiting, training and managing our development staff
- Responsible for selecting, evaluating, and negotiating with technology vendors

Creative Director

LATHAM I SYNCHRONIZED RELATIONSHIP MARKETING (1997-2005)

Latham is a Digital and Direct Marketing Agency serving clients including: Whirlpool, Canon, Toyota, CitiFinancial, and Harrah's Casino.

- Responsible for creative direction of direct marketing, advertising, and interactive campaigns
- Managed a team of art directors, copywriters, and web developers
- Hired and managed a pool of freelance artists and copywriters
- Presented designs internally and to clients
- Designed and developed a proprietary online campaign management interface for clients

Principal, Creative Director

KEVIN CRAWFORD DESIGN (1994-1997)

Digital and Graphic Design for clients including: The Equity Group, Banco Popular, JTC, and Group II Communications

- Provided creative direction for advertising, marketing collateral, package design, multimedia presentation, and film production
- Consulted with clients on marketing strategy
- Managed freelance art directors, photographers, and copywriters
- Responsible for project planning, media buying, client presentations, copywriting, press proofs

Partner, Creative Director

SWISS GRAPHICS (1984-1994)

Graphic Design for clients including: American Academy of Orthopaedic Surgeons, Nation Pizza Products, Inc, Dellsher, and Bank of Chicago

- Key contributor to the company's strategy and planning
- Provided creative direction for corporate identity, advertising, marketing collateral, annual reports, package design, and signage
- Consulted with clients on marketing strategy
- Managed a multi-disciplinary team of art directors, photographers, and copywriters
- Responsible for project planning, media buying, team coordination, client presentations, copywriting, press proofs

Awards

American Business Awards 2012

SILVER STEVIE (NEW PRODUCT OR SERVICE)
WHEELS INC. - "CHANGEDRIVER"

Chicago Innovation Awards 2010

TOUCH TASTE TECHNOLOGIES - "TOUCHLIFE"

Telly Awards 2004

SILVER TELLY (BROADCAST)
DTRIC INSURANCE - "BIG ON YOU"

Tempo Awards 2003

FIRST PLACE (INTERACTIVE MARKETING)
WHIRLPOOL CORPORATION - "HOMEFRONT"

Tempo Awards 2003

FIRST PLACE - (BROADCAST)
DTRIC INSURANCE - "UNBEATABLE"

Eagle Awards 1993

PIONEER BANCORP, INC. (ANNUAL REPORT)

Eagle Awards 1992

PIONEER BANCORP, INC. (ANNUAL REPORT)

DESI Awards 1988

GRAPHIC DESIGN: USA (CORPORATE BROCHURES) TRANSCO PRODUCTS, INC.

Education

Georgia Institute of Technology

BA, INDUSTRIAL DESIGN (1981 – 1985)